A Finding Aid to the Louise Nevelson Papers, circa 1903-1988, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Writings, circa 1936-1980; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; (Box 5, 38, Sol 42; 0.5 linear feet)
  - On Sculpture Education for Children; Artists, 1955, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Artist Statements, circa 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Technical Notes and Sketches, 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Salutes to Others, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Dawns and Dusks: Taped Conversations with Diana MacKown (1976), Quotes, circa 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Dawns and Dusks: Taped Conversations with Diana MacKown (1976), Drafts, circa 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Dawns and Dusks: Taped Conversations with Diana MacKown (1976), Drafts, circa 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Dawns and Dusks: Taped Conversations with Diana MacKown (1976), Drafts; Comment Added, circa 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Louise Nevelson: Atmosphere and Environments (1980), Proof, circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 19)
- Scrapbooks, 1935-1983; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; (Boxes 5, 18-19, OV 22-27, 38, Sol 42; 1.5 linear feet)
  Series consists of scrapbooks kept by Nevelson (or by someone on her behalf), documenting her early career roughly spanning from the 1930s to the mid-1950s. Also included are a scrapbook of sorts on Mike Nevelson, as well as various scrapbooks compiled by others and then presented to Nevelson as a memento of a particular event involving the artist, such as being awarded the Distinguished Service Award from State University College at Buffalo and an exhibition at the Galerie Jeanne Bucher in Paris.
  A lot of the material is duplicated in the different scrapbooks kept by Nevelson. Much of the same and related material can be found amongst printed material.
  Scrapbooks are arranged in rough chronological order. Many were removed from their original bindings at some previous time. Loose clippings and photographs of art work that were originally in scrapbooks, and were likewise removed at some previous time, are arranged in files at the end of the series. More detailed descriptions for certain scrapbooks are provided below. The bulk of this series has been scanned, except for duplicates, photographs of works of art, and some newsclippings. In some cases, only the cover and title pages have been scanned for published items.
  - Scrapbook, Loose Items and Pages, 1918, 1935-1955; Archival Resource Key; (See Box 18) (Box 5, Folder 32)
    Includes Nevelson's high school diploma, a drawing of Nevelson by William Zorach, drawings by Nevelson (reproductions of old masters, which she signed "Berliawsky"), and scrapbook pages of clippings and exhibition catalogs. Note attached reads "Scrapbook, original collation. Acquisition date April 1966."
  - Scrapbook, 1935-1952; Archival Resource Key; (See Box 18) (Box 5, Folder 33)
    Includes clippings (one is an article by Nevelson about her work at the Flatbush Boy's Club, the rest are mostly reviews and listings of exhibitions); announcements and catalogs for various exhibitions (including, notably, her first solo show at the Nierendorf Gallery); and a program and clippings on Mike Nevelson's performance in the play, Our Town.
  - Scrapbook, Loose Pages, 1936-1966 (bulk 1952-1956); Archival Resource Key; (See OV 22-26) (Box 5, Folder 34)
    Includes primarily clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs from the time period 1952-1956 (much of this material is duplicated in this and other scrapbooks), as well as an exhibition catalog for the American Artists Congress show in 1936, an educational bulletin (listing a class taught by Nevelson in 1938-1939), a book of poems (in Spanish) by Alfredo Chaco, and correspondence and clippings relating to an honorary degree received in 1966.
  - Scrapbook, Loose Items and Pages, 1941-1944, 1952, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key; (See OV 27) (Box 5, Folder 35)
    Includes, along with the more typical clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs, photographs (stats?) of models posing in front of Nevelson art work (presumably taken sometime during the 1960s), extensive clippings on Joe Milone and his shoeshine box (discovered by Nevelson in 1942 and exhibited that same year at MOMA), and proofs of the artist photograph (where Nevelson is made up to look like a witch) which appeared in Life magazine sometime in the 1950s.
  - Scrapbook, Japanese Printed Material, 1950s-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Scrapbook, Loose Clippings on Mike Nevelson, 1953-1956; Archival Resource Key; (See Box 19) (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Scrapbook, Distinguised Service Award from State University College at Buffalo, 1968-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Scrapbook, Exhibition at Galerie Jeanne Bucher, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Scrapbook Pages (compiled by Zachary Gitlin), 1969-1970; Archival Resource Key; (See Box 19) (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Loose Clippings Originally in Scrapbooks, 1936-1958; Archival Resource Key; (5 folders; not scanned) (Box 5, Folder 40-44)
  - Loose Photographs of Art Work Originally in Scrapbooks, circa 1940s-1950s; Archival Resource Key; (8 folders; not scanned) (Box 5, Folder 45-52)
  - Oversize, Scrapbook, Loose Items and Pages, 1918, 1935-1955; Archival Resource Key; (See Box 5, F32) (Box 18)
  - Oversize, Scrapbook, 1935-1952; Archival Resource Key; (See Box 5, F33) (Box 18)
  - Oversize, Scrapbook, Loose Pages, 1936-1966; bulk 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key; (See Box 5, F34) (Oversize 22)
  - Oversize, Scrapbook, Loose Pages, 1936-1966; bulk 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 23)
    Scope and Contents
    (See Box 5, F34)
  - Oversize, Scrapbook, Loose Pages, 1936-1966; bulk 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 24)
  - Oversize, Scrapbook, Loose Pages, 1936-1966; bulk 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 25)
  - Oversize, Scrapbook, Loose Pages, 1936-1966; bulk 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 26)
  - Oversize, Scrapbook, Loose Items and Pages, 1941-1944, 1952, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key; (See Box 5, F35) (Oversize 27)
  - Oversize, Scrapbook, Loose Clippings on Mike Nevelson, 1953-1956; Archival Resource Key; (See Box 5, F36) (Box 19)
  - Oversize, Scrapbook Pages (compiled by Zachary Gitlin), 1969-1970; Archival Resource Key; (See Box 5, F39) (Box 19)
  - Scrapbook from Farnsworth Staff, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook from Farnsworth Staff, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 42, Folder 6)
- Books and Printed Material, 1904-1985; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; (Boxes 6-13, 19, OV 28; 8 linear feet)
  Series consists of books and printed material collected by Nevelson and/or her assistants, documenting her various professional and artistic achievements throughout her career, her critical and commercial success, and her role as a personality and minor celebrity in the mass media late in her career. Books include ones given as gifts to Nevelson by friends or admirers and ones about or featuring segments on Nevelson. Printed material includes clippings from magazines and newspapers of reviews, articles, and routine listings of Nevelson's exhibits, as well as some publications featuring the same; exhibition catalogs, announcements, and invitations for Nevelson's group and solo shows, as well as some for the shows of others; and press releases, newsletters, bulletins, announcements, calendars of events, catalogs, programs and other printed material relating or referring to Nevelson or merely featuring her name in print. The extent of this material is suggestive of Nevelson's concern and effort to document and keep a record of her accomplishments.
  Printed material is arranged in rough chronological order according to type. Some material is arranged in files according to subject at the end of the series. The bulk of Nevelson's exhibition catalogs were scanned.
  - Books, 1904-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 38, Folder 21-25)
  - Books, 1961-1977; Archival Resource Key; (11 books; not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Titles include:
    Antologia del possible, Gastone Novelli (1962)
    Art and Sexual Politics: Women's Liberation, Women Artists, and Art History, eds. Thomas B. Hess and Elizabeth C. Baker (1973)
    Icons and Images of the Sixties, Nicolas Calas and Elena Calas (1971)
    Louise Nevelson, Arnold B. Glimcher (1972)
    Nevelson, Colette Roberts (1964)
    New Directions 17, ed. J. Laughlin (1961)
    Open Secrets: Ninety-four Women in Touch with Our Time, Barbaralee Diamonstein (1972)
    The Paper Snake, Ray Johnson (1965)
    Provacative Parallels: Naive Early Americans/International Sophisticates, Jean Lipman (1975)
    Ultime tendenze nell'arte d'oggi, Gillo Dorfles (1961)
    Ventures in Research: Lectures by the Faculty of C.W. Post Center of Long Island University, ed. Richard R. Griffith (1977)
  - Clippings, Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned) (Box 6)
    - Clippings, 1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Clippings, 1940s; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
    - Clippings, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Clippings, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Clippings, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Clippings, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Clippings, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Clippings, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Clippings, 1957; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 11-12)
    - Clippings, 1958; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
    - Clippings, 1959; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 15-17)
    - Clippings, 1960; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 18-20)
    - Clippings, 1961; Archival Resource Key; (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 21-24)
    - Clippings, 1962; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 25-27)
    - Clippings, 1963; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 28-30)
    - Clippings, 1964; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 31-33)
    - Clippings, 1965; Archival Resource Key; (4 folders) (Box 7, Folder 1-4)
    - Clippings, 1966; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 5-7)
    - Clippings, 1967; Archival Resource Key; (4 folders) (Box 7, Folder 8-11)
    - Clippings, 1968; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 12-14)
    - Clippings, 1969; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 15-17)
    - Clippings, 1970; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 18-19)
    - Clippings, 1971; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 20-22)
    - Clippings, 1972; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 23-25)
    - Clippings, 1973; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 26-28)
    - Clippings, 1974; Archival Resource Key; (5 folders) (Box 7, Folder 29-33)
    - Clippings, 1975; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 34-36)
    - Clippings, 1976; Archival Resource Key; (6 folders) (Box 7, Folder 37-42)
    - Clippings, 1977; Archival Resource Key; (7 folders) (Box 8, Folder 1-7)
    - Clippings, 1978; Archival Resource Key; (4 folders) (Box 8, Folder 8-11)
    - Clippings, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Clippings, undated; Archival Resource Key; (6 folders) (Box 8, Folder 13-18)
    - Nevelson Clippings From Farnsworth Art Museum, 1940s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 39, Folder 1-4)
    - Nevelson Show Announcements, 1940s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Galerie of France Show, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Berliawsky and Nevelson Family, 1960s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Regarding Friends and Peers, 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Regarding Nevelson's Assistants, 1976-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Publications, Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned) (Box 8)
    - Publications, 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Publications, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Publications, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Publications, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Publications, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Publications, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Publications, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Publications, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Publications, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Publications, 1967; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 8, Folder 28-30)
    - Publications, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Publications, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Publications, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Publications, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Publications, 1973; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 5-7)
    - Publications, 1974; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 8-10)
    - Publications, 1975; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 11-13)
    - Publications, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Publications, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Publications, 1978; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 16-17)
    - Publications, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Archival Resource Key (Box 9)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1959; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 2-4)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1960; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 5-7)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1961; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1964; Archival Resource Key; (See also Box 19) (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1967; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 15-16)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1969; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 18-19)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1971; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 21-23)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1972; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 24-25)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1973; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1974; Archival Resource Key; (4 folders) (Box 11, Folder 3-6)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1975; Archival Resource Key; (4 folders) (Box 11, Folder 7-10)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1976; Archival Resource Key; (See also Box 19) (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1977; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 12-13)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Exhibition and Collection Catalogs, 1960-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 39, Folder 10-15)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, Archival Resource Key (Box 11)
    - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, 1960s; Archival Resource Key; (5 folders) (Box 11, Folder 19-23)
    - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, 1970s; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
    - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Group and Solo Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, 1940s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 39, Folder 16-18)
  - Artist Cards, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Press Releases, 1944-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Press Releases, 1971-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Press Releases, 1967-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters and Bulletins, 1947-1979; Archival Resource Key; (6 folders; see also Box 19; not scanned) (Box 12, Folder 7-12)
  - Newsletters and Publications, 1970s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 40, Folder 3-4)
  - Newsletters and Publications, 1970s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements for Others, 1951-1970; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 12, Folder 13-14)
  - Events and Exhibitions, 1960s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Exhibition Announcements, Posters, 1954-1977; Archival Resource Key; (4 folders; see also OV 28; not scanned) (Box 12, Folder 15-18)
  - Course Catalogs for Adult Program, Great Neck Public Schools, 1955-1959; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 12, Folder 19-20)
  - Announcements and Calendars of Events, 1958-1978; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 12, Folder 21-22)
  - Auction Catalogs, 1961-1979; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 12, Folder 23-24)
  - Transcript of Panel Discussion Featuring Nevelson, 1961; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned) (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Prospectuses, 1962; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned) (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Programs, 1963-1978; Archival Resource Key; (5 folders; see also Box 19; not scanned) (Box 12, Folder 27-31)
  - Gallery and Exhibition Guides, 1964-1977; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned) (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Reports, 1964-1977; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned) (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Invitations, 1965-1979; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders; not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 1-3)
  - Lists, 1967-1977; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Sample of Nevelson's Portfolio of Original Serigraphs, circa 1968; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Art Catalogs, 1969-1978; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 6-7)
  - Skowhegan Award Dinner Programs, 1971-1979; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 8-9)
  - Agendas, 1973, 1977; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, Personal, 1975-1977, undated; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Book Catalog, 1978-1979; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Greeting Cards, Post Cards, and Drawing Pad Featuring Nevelson's Work, undated; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Photocopied Reproductions of Nevelson Art Work, undated; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material Referring to Nevelson, 1959-1979, undated; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders; not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 15-17)
  - Miscellaneous, 1916, 1957-circa 1973, undated; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - By Subject, Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned) (Box 13)
    - New York Society of Ceramic Arts Exhibition, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Grand Central Moderns, 1957-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Mike Nevelson, 1961-1978; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 13, Folder 21-23)
    - Venice Biennale, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Artists Equity Convention, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - New York Council on the Arts, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - "Plu Kifekler,", 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Pace Gallery, 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Arnold Scaasi Collections, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Walker Art Center Exhibition, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Public Arts Council, 1974, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Sarah Scaife Gallery (Museum of Art, Carnegie Institute), 1974; Archival Resource Key; (See also Box 19) (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Rockefeller Sculpture, 1976-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Art in Architecture Program, 1977-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Embarcadero Center, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Art and Community Institute Advisory Board, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Little Italy Restoration Association, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - New York Feminist Art Institute, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Oversize, Exhibition Catalogs, 1964; Archival Resource Key; (See Box 10, F12) (Box 19)
  - Oversize, Exhibition Catalogs, 1976; Archival Resource Key; (See Box 11, F11) (Box 19)
  - Oversize, Newsletters and Bulletins, 1947-1979; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned) (Box 19)
  - Oversize, Programs, 1963-1978; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned) (Box 19)
  - Oversize, By Subject, Sarah Scaife Gallery (Museum of Art, Carnegie Institute), 1974; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned) (Box 19)
  - Oversize, Exhibition Announcements, Posters, 1954-1977; Archival Resource Key; (Not scanned) (Oversize 28)
  - Exhibition Posters, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 43, Folder 1)
- Art Work, 1905-1982; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; (Boxes 13, 20, 40, Sol 43; 0.5 linear feet)
  Series consists of some of Nevelson's early art work. Included are drawings she made as a child and adolescent; watercolor copies of Old Master paintings (including a slightly changed version of the Mona Lisa), watercolor landscapes, and drawings of period furniture created while she was taking art classes in high school; various watercolors created while she was studying art in the 1920s; and four printing plates mounted on wood blocks, presumably used in making relief prints of certain Nevelson sculptures. Art work found here documents Nevelson's artistic tendencies as a youth and her early development as an artist, and provides an interesting contrast to the later work for which she became famous.
  Also included are illustrated holiday and greeting cards, sketchbooks, and other pieces of art gifted to Nevelson by her friends, peers, and assistant Teddy Haseltine; and two copies of Louise Nevelson: Geometry + Magic, a portrait of Louise Nevelson filmed over four years by Diana MacKown and Rawn Fulton (1982).
  Art work is arranged in chronological order according to type. All of Nevelson's art work in this series has been scanned in its entirety, except for printing plates.
  - Childhood Drawings, 1905-1916; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Watercolors and Drawings, Old Masters, 1916; Archival Resource Key; (See also Box 20) (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Watercolors, Landscapes, 1916-1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Drawings, Period Furniture, 1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 42)